<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Notes on Nico Einsidler.</title><link>https://ne555.io/notes/</link><description>Recent content in Notes on Nico Einsidler.</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Feb 2022 13:52:46 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ne555.io/notes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>qRAM</title><link>https://ne555.io/notes/qram/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Feb 2022 13:52:46 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://ne555.io/notes/qram/</guid><description>A concept of a quantum random access memory was first proposed in 2007. It offers a way to randomly address $N=2^n$ data cells with $n$ bits.
Basic Idea The basic idea of qRAM is to use address qubits to point to some data in a data qubit register. Encoding of the information in the data register can be done by using controlled gates on the data register (if the information is consisting of only 0&amp;rsquo;s and 1&amp;rsquo;s CNOT gates are used).</description></item><item><title>WezTerm</title><link>https://ne555.io/notes/wezterm/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Jan 2022 15:14:57 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://ne555.io/notes/wezterm/</guid><description>I found a new terminal: WezTerm. Not as fast as Alacritty it&amp;rsquo;s still GPU accelerated and has some great features.
WezTerm combines two important aspects: Alacritties speed and iTerms/GNOME Terminals tabs. It sure isn&amp;rsquo;t as fast as Alacritty, but in my daily usage, I hardly notice any differences.
Noteworthy features:
GPU accelerated tabs good font support (it supports ligatures as well) easy theming simple configuration (via a wezterm.lua file in $HOME/.</description></item><item><title>Podman All the Things</title><link>https://ne555.io/notes/podman-all-the-things/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Dec 2021 01:33:10 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://ne555.io/notes/podman-all-the-things/</guid><description>A few days ago while browsing lobste.rs I stumbled upon the article &amp;ldquo;Dock Life: Using Docker for All The Things!&amp;quot; written by Andrew Welch. It had then gotten onto the upper half of the first page on lobste.rs and a few days ago even Chris Coyer from CSS-Tricks.com wrote about it.
Just coming from NixOS and Fedora Silverblue, I was immediately hooked. This is actually an amazing idea!
Basic Idea The basic idea behind Andrew Welch&amp;rsquo;s article is simple: If you ever need to run a certain program, grab a container that already includes the desired program and remap the program name on your system to a docker run command.</description></item><item><title>Selling Products</title><link>https://ne555.io/notes/selling-products/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Nov 2021 20:07:38 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://ne555.io/notes/selling-products/</guid><description>Selling stuff is just a byproduct of creating cool products.</description></item><item><title>DNF Config</title><link>https://ne555.io/notes/dnf-config/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Nov 2021 19:07:18 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://ne555.io/notes/dnf-config/</guid><description>The DNF package manager posses a config file under /etc/dnf/dnf.config. A few interesting options are available and not set per default.
# force the usage of fastest mirror available fastestmirror=True # enable parallel downloads to speed up downloads max_parallel_downloads=10 # enable colored output color=&amp;#34;always&amp;#34;</description></item></channel></rss>